# Edwin Dan Lopez Web Designer / Front-end Dev

I help businesses build their presence by developing modern websites and UI

Mello@edwindanlopez.com

**\( 208.794.3982** 

edwindanlopez.com

github.com/edwindanlopez

# **Summary**

Having the experience of working in creative agencies, in-house departments, and full-time remote positions give me valuable insight into web, graphic, and UI design. I have also expanded my knowledge in front-end development through self-study and freelance projects building web apps and modern stack websites. This furthers my goals of bringing quality experiences and clear communication to end-users.

# **Experience**

#### Lead Web Designer - GetTheGuy - (Apr 2022 - Present) (FL)

- ♦ Design and build landing pages for marketing funnels and user opt-ins, using a combination of HTML, CSS, Javascript, and Wordpress builders like Divi and Elementor
- Design and develop email templates for use in marketing emails
- Assist and lead in other design related projects

#### Self-Study - (2021 - Present) (FL)

- ♦ Further education and knowledge in development and programming
- ♦ Epic React workshops (Certificates)
- ♦ Testing JavaScript workshops
- ♦ Egghead:
  - Advanced TypeScript fundamentals, Chrome DevTools Debugging,
  - ♦ Next Js, Svelte Js, Tailwind CSS, ChakraUI
- ♦ Books, tutorials, and Readings:
  - Elequent JavaScript, TypeScript, GraphQL, MongoDb, FaunaDB, Groq

# Trading Ally Journaling App - Study project (Dec 2021 - Present) (FL)

- ♦ Trading Ally is a React application that allows users to log their latest stock trades
- ♦ Incorporate reusable functional components and follow best-practices in passing data between component UI
- Integrate with Fauna DB for data storage
- Integrate Typescript to help increase efficiency in maintainability
- Ongoing plans include:
  - Integrating with Netlify ID for user authentication
  - ♦ Integrating with the TD Ameritrade API to automatically log trades for users with a ThinkorSwim account

#### El Jefe Birria & Tacos Landing Page - Freelance (Nov 2021) (OR)

♦ Design and build a Wordpress landing page for El Jefe's menu options

#### Front-end Developer - BBS Website - Freelance (Sep 2021 - Nov 2021) (FL)

- Provide a consistent yet flexible website solution that allows the business to start small and grow it's online portfolio over time i.e. (Simple layout, category pages, and search tags to expand filtering in the future)
- Provide a combination of libraries and frameworks that will allow for image heavy content without sacrificing speed or user experience (Image optimization, static site generation, and caching)

#### **Education**

## 2018 University of Central Florida

M.E.R.N. Stack Web **Developer Certificate** 

# **2014 Graduate of Pacific** Union College (BFA)

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Graphic Design

### **Skills**

#### **Programming Languages**

- ♦ Javascript
- ♦ Typescript
- ♦ HTML
- ♦ CSS

#### Frameworks & Libraries

- ♦ React
- ♦ Gatsby
- ♦ Node JS
- Svelte

#### **Tools & Platforms**

- ♦ Git
- ♦ Vercel
- ♦ Netlify
- ♦ Wordpress
- ♦ Sanity
- ♦ Auth0

#### **Design & Prototype**

- ♦ Figma
- ♦ XD
- ♦ Framer
- ♦ Sketch
- ♦ Adobe AI, PS, ID

# **Experience (Continued)**

- Develop a solution that will allow users to send images or videos of their potential projects for a quote or estimate (3rd party integration)
- ♦ Provide a modern contact form solution with sanitation, validation, and automatic email confirmation response (Library and 3rd party integration)
- Provide on-going website maintenance

#### Senior Web, UI, and Graphic Designer - The DiSTI Corporation (Jul 2019 - Jul 2021) (FL)

- Ideate and restructure website content
- Design and prototype company website for clean developer hand-off
- ♦ Design software product iconography, loading screen, and splash screen
- Create and manage print and digital assets for large trade show events including landing pages, trade show booths, social media and other promotional content
- ♦ Design day-to-day marketing collateral such as brochures, info-graphics, banners, posters and press releases

#### Web Production Management - TT Publications (May 2018 - Jul 2019) (FL)

- Lead the design and production of Wordpress websites
- Provide in-house maintenance, support and client training after build
- Provide assistance with logo and marketing designs
- Lead project introduction, set milestones and guide projects through deadlines working with third party vendors and developers

#### Web & Graphic Design - Freelance (Oct 2017- May 2018) (OR)

- Create branding, marketing assets and provide website development for several clients ranging from a non-profit organization to an emerging musical artist
- Contract with several agencies assisting with website design, email HTML custom template development and marketing collateral design

#### UI, Web, and Graphic Design - Watson Creative (Oct 2015 - Sep 2017) (OR)

- Design and develop branding strategies, websites, and landing pages along with any other print and digital marketing deliverable
- Prepare mobile and tablet website breakdowns for developer hand-off
- Help train clients use Wordpress CMS
- ♦ Ideate and collaborate in weekly design sprints and critique meetings

### Jr. Designer at Fieldtrip Inc. (Feb 2015 - May 2015) (OR)

- ♦ Ideate and design brand identities, websites, Word booklets and PowerPoint templates along with required marketing graphics
- Design and develop company RFPs

#### CF Napa Brand Design Intern (Aug 2014 - Nov 2014) (CA)

- ♦ Develop competitive typography sets for packaging and display signage
- Ideate packaging labels, logos, crests and symbol specific to the food and beverage industry
- Design presentation decks for proposals and client meetings
- Mock-up label and packaging designs on different mediums

#### **Traits**

- ♦ Thrives in a collaborative environment
- ♦ Focused on sprint objectives
- ♦ Well organized
- Communicates in a concise manner
- ♦ Possesses a hunger to learn and grow



Web Designer / Front-end Dev